Russian-Japanese war the Japanese they are like the
русско-японская война японцы они как
Slavs, too, as I understand it, they fought hard
славяне тоже я так понимаю сильно бились
and
и
won Hello Hello, I’m from the
выиграли Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из
city of Khmelnitsky Where are you from? I’m from the city of
города Хмельницкий Вы откуда Я из города
Novosibir.
Новосибир счм беседуете прикольно
drones destroyed the ship Russian
дроны уничтожили корабль российский
heard did not see
слышал не видел
confirmation there video Well, ours
подтверждения там видео Ну наши же
called out
выкликал
there then he rises like this in
там потом он такой поднимается в
the thermal imager in short, probably the battle set
тепловизоре короче наверное боя комплект
hit yes yes They just hit the
попали да да Они так именно раз ударили
same point and the same and the fourth yes The
в Тоту же точку и в ту же и четвёртый да
third one to the same Well done  well done guys are not
Третий в ту же Ну молодцы молодцы не
so useless I think the question is yes Question
такие бесполезные думаю вопрос да Вопрос
How is it that in the second year of its
Как так получается что на втором году
Yes Ukraine continues to destroy the
сво Да Украина продолжает уничтожать
Black Sea Fleet is hitting the Leningrad
Черноморский флот лупит в Ленинградскую
region is hitting the Nizhny Novgorod region Well, the Ukrainians, after
область лупит в Нижегородскую область
all, the
Ну украинцы всё-таки
Slavs know how to fight adapt
славяне умеют воевать приспосабливаться
Well done and not the Slavs don’t know how the Mongols don’t
Молодцы а не славяне не умеют монголы не
know how to fight Yes  for example, well, simply As
умеют воевать Да например ну просто Как
practice shows, Europeans give up
показывает практика европейцы сдаются
before they should, it’s as if they don’t have
раньше положенного у них как будто нет
rods to hold, as if they were holding it, that
стержни держать держал как будто То есть
is, for example, are the Poles Europeans or Slavs? Well, they are Slavs, that is, the Poles don’t
славяне Ну они славяне то есть поляки не
give up. Yes, just like the Europeans. Well, a miracle hung
сдаются Да как европейцы Ну чудо нависли
there, too, well done,
там тоже
I understood correctly  what
молодцы то я правильно понял что
happens Everything that comes next Poland there
получается Всё что дальше Польша там
Germany France Italy they don’t seem to have
Германия Франция Италия они уже типа нет
them anymore Darling
у них Душка
Yes, it’s difficult to say so, but from what
Да сложно так сказать но из того что
world practice shows, it seems like
показывает мировая практика как будто бы
no Yeah, that is, well, in world practice Yes,
нет Угу то есть ну в мировой практике Да
there are such myths there, for example, like
есть такие мифы там там например как
King Leoni Yes  and 300 Spartans surrendered
король леони Да и 300 спартанцев сдались
quickly, yes And about the Roman army in general,
быстро да А про Римское войско вообще
it surrendered Every time when it
оно сдавало Каждый раз когда куда-то
got somewhere, in principle, well, the Europeans are not
попадало в принципе да ну европейцы не
like that, well, I’m not saying, I don’t remember
так ну я же не говорю я же не вспоминаю
these are generally other eras, everything was
это вообще другие эпохи там всё было
different there, in general, I understand But it’s interesting
по-другому вообщем понял А интересно
when, for example, let's say that the Third
когда вот например давайте так Третий
Reich surrendered quickly
рейх сдавался быстро
and the Third Reich is just an
а третий рейх это как раз-таки
exception for very obvious reasons, and
исключение по очень понятным причинам а
they were Slavs, and they were
они славяне были да это были первые
probably the first Europeans who were very
наверное европейцы которые были очень
strictly charged with ideology,
жёстко заряжены идеологией
yeah, so interesting. In short, I understood
угу вот так так интересно Короче я понял
In general, everything is like  All Europeans are
В общем все типа все европейцы они с
Kuna and Slavs In short, they are there Yes, I’m not
куны а славяне Короче они там Да не я не
saying that they are Sukunas, but just As it
говорю что сукуны но просто Как
shows Well, what I read are many
показывает Ну то что я читал многие
conflicts, wars there are different, but
конфликты войны там различные но
For example, I Well, of course, I
Например я Ну понятно украинцев я вообще
don’t take the Ukrainians at all, they were in the Russian Empire Yes,
не беру они были в Российской империи Да
always when when  there were wars there of the
всегда когда когда были войны там
Russian Tsardom of the Russian
Русского царства Российской
Empire Well, they kept them right there until
империи Ну там прям держали прям до
the last, that is, once again so you are there Chita I’m
последнего то есть ещ раз так что вы там
wondering what books you
Чита Мне интересно какие книжки вы
read, what about bad Europeans, well,
читали что там про плохих европей ну
tell me, I’m interested in what
расскажите мне интересно про какие во
books are in it, I just know
это книжки это я просто ну знаю
the conflicts there  just what kind of conflicts What
конфликты там раз какие конфликты Какие
conflicts are the Napoleonic Wars there yes
конфликты Наполеоновские войны там да
So what stop stop stop what
Так что Что стоп стоп стоп что в
was wrong with
наполеоновских Войнах было не так с
the Europeans in the Napoleonic Wars the French went through all of Europe and
европейцами французы прошли всю Европу и
were stuck only with us wait
застряли только у нас подождите
wait Stop who fought in the
подождите Стоп кто воевал в
Napoleonic
наполеоновских
Wars well all of Europe
Войнах ну вся Европа
almost all of Europe fought but
практически вся вся Европа воевала но
they are
они
weaklings Well, they just gave up very
слабаки Ну они просто сдавались очень
quickly, unlike the
быстро в отличие от
Russians So,
русских Так а ну
tell me, you can tell me In the
расскажите можете мне сказать Вот в
Napoleonic Wars Yes, the heroic
наполеоновских Войнах Да героическая
defense of Moscow by the Russians from Napoleon,
оборона Москвы русскими от Наполеона
you can tell this
можете рассказать этот
episode was a heroic battle in
эпизод была героическая битва
nature This is only later this is later
природном Это уже потом это уже потом
Tell me how the Russians did not surrender  in
вот Скажите как русские не сдались в
Moscow How the Russians didn’t surrender to Napoleon in
Москве Как русские не сдали наполеону в
Moscow, you can tell me that we
Москву можете рассказать мне это мы из
didn’t surrender from Moscow, we just retreated, ran away,
Москвы не сдавались мы просто отступили
left the city to be
убежали оставили город на
plundered, don’t say that we fled from
разграбление Не ну сказать что бежали из
Bach, wait, that is, look, that is,
Бах про подожди то есть смотри То есть
you just admitted that the Russians didn’t
ты только что признал что россияне Да не
stand for
стояли за
Moscow, after all, they are weaklings, but they quickly surrendered and ran away.
Москву вс-таки они слабаки да быстро
Well, I’m explaining, you don’t
сдались убежали Ну я же объясняю ты не
hear, but probably
слышишь да наверное смотри Так слыши ну
look. So, listen, well, they ran away, look, in war there is such a
убежали есть смотри э в войне есть такое
thing as tactics and strategy. You
понятие как тактика и стратегия Ты
must win strategically; tactically,
должен победить стратегически тактически
you can make many unpopular
ты можешь делать многие непопулярные
decisions; But strategically you  I have to
решения Но стратегически ты должен всё
calculate everything so that I can win, so that’s what we
рассчитать так чтобы победить так вот мы
did. Yeah, you understand.
так и сделали Угу понимаешь понял
Tell us how the Russians did in the First
Расскажите как русские сделали в Первую
World
мировую
War, did what? Well, how they did it,
войну сделали что Ну как они сделали
for example, that is, as I understand it, the
например то есть я так понимаю что
Russians lost the First World War. Yes, in the
русские же проиграли Первую мировую Да в
First World War, we entered into an
Первую мировую войну Мы заключили
agreement with  the Germans call it
договор с немцами называется Брестский
Brest-Litovsk correctly Yes Brest Yes
брест-литовский правильно Да Брестский
we concluded it because we
Да мы его заключили потому что у нас
lost because we
проиграли потому что
lost No we concluded it but you concluded it on
проиграли Нет мы его заключили по вы на
German terms yes I’m
немецких условиях заключили да Я же
explaining Well, you’re listening Well, on
объясняю Ну вы слушаете Так ну на
German terms we explained this peace
немецких условиях объяснили этот мирный
treaty on German terms
договор на немецких условиях
I’ll explain clearly what was in this agreement.
объясняю поди в этом договоре что было
Ukraine was recognized as an independent
Украина признавалась независимым
state. As far as I remember, Yes, it
государством Насколько помню Да
was recognized, yes. That is, you lost to
признавалась да То есть вы проиграли
Germany and Germany on its own terms. Yes, it stood,
Германии и Германия на своих условиях Да
for example, that it was recognized. That is,
она стояла например что признали То есть
you lost. Yes, that’s right. Now I’ll explain
вы проиграли Да всё верно Это объясняю
why this happened, this
теперь почему это произошло это
happened because  we were in the midst of a
произошло потому что у нас в разгаре шла
civil
гражданская
war, look, this no longer
война смотри Это уже никого не
interests anyone. There is a tactic, a strategy,
интересует Есть тактика стратегия
you understand, the Germans. Yes, the Germans just
понимаешь немцы Да немцы просто
tactically made you a civil war. Well, look, you know
тактически сделали вам гражданскую войну
this story,
ну смотрите это ж вы знаете эту историю
how the Germans sent you revolutionaries, you
как немцы прислали вам революционеров
can really say so. Yes, there is such a
правда можно так сказать Да есть такая
Ver. Yes, the Germans you  they beat you tactically and
Вер Да немцы вас обыграли тактически и
strategically, that is, what was going on with you?
стратегически то есть что у вас там шло
No one is interested anymore. You
Это уже никого не интересует вы
signed a shameful peace treaty. Yes, I
подписали позорный мирный договор Да
lost, I understand, it’s interesting. Yes, you can do the
проиграл понял согла интересненько Да
Russo-Japanese War. So I
русско-японская война можете Вот я так
understand that the Russo-Japanese War, the Japanese
понимаю что русско-японская война японцы
are like Slavs, too, as I understand it
они как славяне тоже я так понимаю
strongly  they fought and won, or rather they didn’t
сильно бились и выиграли Точнее не
win, but Russia lost the
выиграли а Россия с позором проиграла
Russo-Japanese War in disgrace,
русско-японскую войну
so no, not in disgrace, there were
так там нет там не с позором там были
long negotiations, but the Japanese demanded
переговоры долгие вот японцы требовали
one thing in the negotiations but didn’t get it, and
одно по переговорам но не получили этого
well, they won anyway, and part of
и Ну всё равно они победили и часть
Sakhalin is some land there  They, that
Сахалина там какие-то земли Они то
is, in the Russian-Japanese War of 9905,
есть в русско-японской войне 9905 года
yes, Russia to the Slavs and the Japanese. It’s interesting, but
да Россия славянам а японцам Интересно а
in the Crimean War, can you say who
в Крымской войне можете сказать кто
won in almost all the Crimean Wars? Well, in
победил почти во всех Крымских Войнах Ну
general, with
Войнах вообще
these wars with the Turks, we won,
с этими с турками мы побеждали
mole, some French,
кроту какие-то там французы англичане
some British, not Slavs
какие-то не славяне
there, too, and there was no defeat,
там там тоже причём не было поражения
there were
там были
treaties. Yes, like a defeat, because we
договоры Да как поражение потому что мы
didn’t achieve our goal there, too, and not only did
там не добились своего тоже да не то что
n’t you achieve it, you lost
не добились вы потеряли
yours, that is, look, I understood correctly.
свою да то есть смотри я правильно понял
Look, I immediately found it when the French and
Смотри я сходу Да нашёл когда французы и
the British slapped the Russian Slavs in  In the
англичане надавали русским славянам в
Crimean War, the Japanese pushed the Slavs
Крымской войне японцы надавали славянам
in the Russian-Japanese War. Yes, in the
в в русско-японской войне Да эти в
First World War the Germans pushed it, it turns out the
первом мировой немцы надавали получается
Russians. Damn, something in short is not
русским Блин что-то короче у русских не
going well with the Russians. Maybe when? I understand, maybe
ладится Может когда А я понял может
once upon a time during the time of Napoleon there were
когда-то во времена Наполеона были вот
Slavs in Russia who were there and here
на Руси славяне которые там ну тут
you see what’s the matter when there was a Japanese
видите в чём дело когда была японская
war there, in fact, we not only fought with Japan
война там по сути Мы не только с Японией
because
воевали потому что там активно им
Western countries actively helped them there, this time in the war of
помогали западные страны это раз в войне
which you said the Crimean, the British and
которой вы сказали крымскую англичане и
French even fought against
французы войсками даже воевали против
us with troops so about the Lower Slavs Not
нас так о Нижне славяне Не
weaklings, excuse me  even Leo is being extinguished by the crowd, I
слабаки ну извините меня толпой гасят
understand, I understand. Can you tell me
даже Льва понял понял А можете сказать
with whom in the crowd you were extinguishing
с кем в толпе вы гасили
Napoleon? We were in an alliance with the British
Наполеона Мы были в союзе с англичанами
and the
с
Russians, that is, in the crowd you see, you
руссами то есть в толпе видите Вы в
were extinguishing Leo in the crowd, it’s true. No, not really
толпе валили Льва правда Нет не совсем
because, well, in Russia we
так потому что ну при в России мы
fought only with Russians.  we have one more
воевали только русскими то есть нам ещё
time, look again, the coalition was against
раз ещё раз смотри коалиция была против
Napoleon Yes, of course And they would have fought in
Наполеона Да конечно И воевали на
different
разных
battles, the Russians would have howled
битло бы русски
at Waterlow No, I also think that
вой при ватерлоу Нет я тоже думаю что
no, it’s true
нет правда
No, well, it was essentially already a desperate
Не ну это по сути уже была Отчаянная
attempt
попытка
to grab onto the ground, let’s say Napoleon,
ухватиться за землю скажем так Наполеона
he was no longer the same  he was no longer the same Yes,
Он уже был не тот он уже был не тот Да
Napoleon was no longer a cake yes Can you tell me
Наполеон уже был не торт да А можете мне
yes, look, let me see that when
да вот смотри давайте я смотрю что когда
Russia was not in a coalition with Western
Россия была не в коалиции с западными
countries Yes, it
странами Да она очень хорошо
died down very well No, it just so happened that
отгремел Нет просто так сложилось что
countries united against us And you can, yes you
против нас объединялись страны А може
can  say when you what kind of
можете да можете сказать когда вы какую
war you won on your
войну
own, on your
самостоятельно
own, on your own No, well, in principle, you can
самостоятельно Не ну в принципе можно
say in the Second World War we defeated the
сказать во второй мировой мы победили
Germans on our own, not at all
немцев самостоятельно вообще не само
what kind of Germans you are kidding yourself
каких немцев самостоятельно что
Well, the Second Front was opened on the forty-
Ну Второй фронт был открыт сорок
fourth again, look again
четвёртом го ещё раз ещё раз смотри ты
now, in all seriousness when  the Germans
сейчас на полном серьёзе когда немцы
fought Since the year thirty-nine Yes, you
воевали С тридцать девятого года Да вы
entered the war in the forty-first Yes, you are
вступили войну в соро первом Да ты
now saying in all seriousness that you were the
сейчас на полном серьёзе говоришь что вы
only ones who defeated the
единственные побороли
Germans, practically the only ones, that is, let’s do
немцев практически единственные то есть
this England didn’t fight the
давай так Англия не боролась с
Germans, practically no USA didn’t
германи практически нет США не
fight, I’m talking forty whose year they started
боролась я говорю соро чей год начали
opening the second In short  all these British
открыли второй Короче все эти британские
colonies did not fight there England Oh, this is
колонии не боролись там Англия Ой это
Zealand Australia Look at the number of
Зеландия Австралия Посмотрите количество
troops in Africa I’m just
войск на африканском Я просто просто
asking, that is, it turns out with whom
спрашиваю то есть получается с кем тогда
Hitler fought with the Soviet Union on the African front then, the British,
на африканском фронте воевал Гитлер с
so that means after all there
союзом англичане так то значит всё-таки
was a coalition at war Well, you’re a little
воевала была коалиция Ну вы вы маленько
This  Open
Это Откройте
Wikipedia, read the number of troops
Википедию почитайте количество войск
that were there literally, it was
которое там было там буквально было
probably 5% or otherwise it turns out
наверно 5% или а то есть получается
only I understood the British. In short,
только Всё я понял англичан Короче вот
look. So how many states were in the
смотри Так сколько государств ходило в
anti-Hitler
антигитлеровскую
coalition, I don’t know the number, she was in
коалицию я количество не знаю она в
1942 Yes,
сорок втором году Да Типа
she’s not like them  de facto de jura they
она не то что они де-факто деюра
declared war and de facto they didn’t fight, these are
объявили войну а де-факто не воевали это
different things No wait, well, as
разные вещи Нет подожди ну как сказал
Churchill said Well, Fulton’s speech from his speech
Черчиль Ну фултонской речи из его речи
More precisely, we can conclude that he wanted to
Точнее можно сделать вывод что он хотел
defeat communism with the hands of the Germans, that’s
руками немцев победить коммунизм вот и
all, that’s why they are not together Look, I’m looking at the
всё поэтому они не вме Смотри я смотрю
map Yes
карта Да
uh countries of the anti-Hitler coalition,
ээ стран антигитлеровской коалиции вот
Wikipedia is stupid there In short, everything is
Википедии там тупо Короче всё
green
зелёненькое
Except for those who Well, there
Кроме тех кто Ну за Германию
were really very few countries for Germany, there were
реально мало-мало стран было страны
ROSI countries, almost the whole world it was the
РОСИ почти весь мир это была
Anti-Hitler
Антигитлеровская
coalition Well, on paper it can
коалиция Ну она на бумаге может что
be anything, it’s on the boom not on paper,
угодно быть раскас на бума не на бумаге
just tell me  od a war without a
давай скажи мне хоть од войну без
coalition with others so that you don’t
коалиции с другими чтобы вы не толпой
beat someone in a crowd there’s a bunch of people over there, even you know Well,
били кого-то куча вон там даже зна Ну
a bunch of tell Tell the Tatars fought with the Tatars, how many of those Tatars are
куча скажи Скажи с татарами воевали
there in general like
татары сколько там тех татар вообще типа
what kind of serious war
какую вы серьёзную войну серьёзным
did you win with a serious enemy like against the
противником выиграли типа против вот от
Japanese from rowing from the French with
японцев от гребли от французов с
by the British in the Crimean War from rowing from
англичанами в Крымской войне от гребли у
whom you won Well, the Swedes the Swedes I’ll come up
кого вы выиграли Ну шведы шведы подойду
the Swedes
шведы
where the Northern War Well, what kind of war Peter I
где Северная война Ну какая война Пётр I
fought Yes, what war is
Да сражался война какая
called the Northern War Northern
э называется Северная война Северная
War Let’s look now, like that’s what it’s
война Давайте смотрим сейчас вроде так
called if I don’t
называется если я не по
Yes, look at the Great Northern War
так вот смотрите Северная война Великая
here is a twenty-year war, a war that lasted
вот двадцатилетняя война война длившаяся
between the Swedish kingdom and a coalition of
между шведским королевством и коалиции
states of Northern Europe, Saxony, the
государств Северной Европы саксония
Russian kingdom, Dasco, the
русское царство даско норвежское
kingdom of Norway, the Commonwealth, that is, you
королевство речь посполитая То есть вы
defeated Carlo, not Peter I, but the
победили Карло не Пётр I а победила
coalition of European
коалиция европейских
states of large states of sweat won.
государств крупных государство поте
stop stop again you are in the
стоп стоп ещё раз ты ты в
Russian-Japanese you go well they beat us there
русско-японской ты го ну нас били там
together that’s why there is a lion in the crowd So this is
вместе поэтому там и льва толпой Так вы
where you won you were right in the
вот где вы выигрывали вы были как раз в
crowd of civilized strong countries
толпе цивилизованных сильных стран
you didn’t defeat Charles and you didn’t
не вы победили Карла да не вы швецию
defeat Sweden but the coalition actually won  there
победили а победила коалиция реально там
were still a lot of enemies of Sweden around Sweden. Yes,
вокруг Швеции куча ещё было врагов
who fought against it,
Швеции Да которые боролись с ней так
so tell me at least one war that
вот назовите мне хоть одну войну которую
you won not as part of a coalition, but by yourself.
вы выиграли не в составе коалиции а сами
Now I’ll try to
Вот как сейчас я попробую ещ раз
explain again, you just don’t understand, look at
обяснить просто не понимаете смотрите
any war that has been going on there for the last
любая война которая идт последние там
400 years of war
400 лет войны
all the wounds are against one country,
все нено раны против одной страны
you understand, there are always some
понимаете всегда есть какие-то
interested parties who help this
интересант которые помогают там этой
side or that side. Therefore, on Wikipedia Where do
стороне или этой Поэтому в Википедии Где
you get the information, apparently there
вы берёте видимо информацию всегда
will always be someone written who is on this
всегда будет кто-то написан кто этой
side then I don’t understand why then
стороне тогда я не понимаю почему тогда
you are offended that in the Russian-Japanese  during the war
обижаетесь что в русско-японской войне
for the Japanese, there were someone else there,
за японцев были там ещё кто-то ну потому
well, because we were alone, it’s just that usually when there
что мы были одни просто Обычно когда
is a war,
идёт войны
there is this side and there is this side,
есть этой стороны а есть этой стороны
but in this case we were completely alone and there was
Но в данном случае мы были одни совсем а
no Japanese, you know, seriously, yes, let’s
нет понимаете серьёзно
look at it like that, nope,
да Давайте посмотрим так не Нифига
look, we’re not
смотри не
alone for  Japan was the British Empire
одни за Японию была британская Империя
for Russia there was the Principality of Montenegro and the
за Россию было княжество Черногория и
Principality of Bulgaria were not alone already
княжество Болгария не одни уже были уже
in the colony again you see any conflict I will
в колии опять видите вы любой конфликт
open I really Yes I look, that is, I
откроете я реально Да смотрю то есть
really look at the thing I for example don’t know
реально смотрю на вещ Я например не знаю
I open Yes indeed That is, it turns out to
Я открываю Да действительно То есть
be a coalition of the Japanese with the British
получается коалиция японцев с британцами
they gave you [ __ ] Well, look, you
дали вам пиздюлей Ну смотрите вы так
won’t learn anything, you
ничему не научитесь вы всегда когда
will always open it I
будете открывать Я
don’t need to teach you, I know everything, there
вас не не надо меня учить я всё знаю
will always be some interesting people, plus Come on, let’s talk
деюра всегда будет какие-то интересант
about the deura and
плю Давай давайте давайте про деюра и
talk about what is written on the papers,
говорить то что запечатлено на бумагах
who was with whom,
кто с кем был
listen  dejura dejura there the French fought with the Germans,
слушайте деюра деюра там с немцами
who surrendered literally
французы которые сдались буквально
almost instantly, and not only did they
практически мгновенно и причём не только
surrender, but more Frenchmen died
сдались а больше французов погибло
defending Hitler’s regime than in the fight against
защищая режим Гитлера чем в борьбе с
Hitler. I wonder if they recorded how
Гитлером Интересно а они записаны как
they fought. Vova, so so so yes. You
они воевали Вова так так так да
see, in the World Cup a
Понимаете в ЧМ
couple Well, I just  explained Well,
пара Ну я же только что объяснил Ну
how can I explain
както пому объяснять
defending Hitler? And where did they defend
защищая Гитлера А где они защищали
Hitler? Just at the end of the rest, literally
Гитлера Вот как раз реста в конце
before the complete
буквально перед сдачей полной
surrender, they defended a French regiment and
капитуляции обороняли французский полк и
one of the Balts, how
кто-то из прибалтов сколько там
many French died there? Well, Google hundreds of thousands
французов погибло Ну Погугли сотни тысяч
were posted near the Reichstag, hundreds of
были заги возле рейхстага погибло сотни
thousands died in total not  near the Reichstag near the
тысяч в сумме не возле рейхстага возле
Reichstag I don’t remember how much Why do I need
рейхстага я не помню сколько Зачем мне
this in short look uh I understand
это ко короче смотрите ээ Я так понял
that we unwound yours very beautifully This is
что мы очень красиво размотали ваше Вот
Slavic Greatness Yes it turned out that
это Славянское Величие Да оказалось что
uh you Yes it really
ээ вы Да реально
died down I just in short as much as a mother
отгремела вя просто короче аж как мама
don’t cry Yes it turned out that it
не горюй Да оказалось что это
died down in  coalitions Yes, but it turns out
отгремели в коалициях Да но оказывается
that you won only in
что выигрывали Вы только в
coalitions Well,
коалициях Ну вам серьёзными серьёзными
you can’t be processed by serious serious developed states, you ca
государствами развитыми вас уже не
n’t be washed, or rather, I’m fine, you’re
не промыть точнее нормально меня вы вы
not a
не
promoter of this Yes, it didn’t win in an alliance with
промоера сия Да победила не в союзе с
developed These are other
развитыми Вот такими другими
states Yeah, developed Yes yes Well, I’m me
государствами Угу развитыми Да да Ну я я
in principle  I understand what you want to say.
в принципе понял что хотите сказать
Let's go to the next one:
Давайте следующую те что что
what, what, well, you came up with something for yourself
что ну вы сами себе что-то там придумали
and you believe in it. So what I want to say is, well,
и в это верите ра Так что я хочу сказать
voice
Ну озвучьте
it out, well, I understood everything, but you think,
это ну я я всё понял но вы считаете вот
look, you look, I Well, I explained it for the
смотрите вы смотрите я Ну я объяснил
third time  I’ll say okay, you just opened
третий раз скажу ладно вы сейчас открыли
Wikipedia and look, they fought for this side
Википедию и смотрите вот за эту сторону
And for this side Yes, I’m looking at the facts, and
воевали И за эту сторону Да я факта
I just explained to you using the example of the French
смотрю вот а я вам на примере французов
that the French are
сейчас объяснил что французы они
recorded as fighting against Hitler,
записаны как боролись что против Гитлера
but in fact the French
боролись Но на самом деле французы
fought more against the Soviet Union
больше боролись против Советского Союза
you don’t want to understand this ViDi okay how much
вы это не хотите понять ВиДи хорошо
Let’s So how many French
сколько Давайте Так сколько французов
died in the fight against the Soviet Union and
погибло в борьбе с советским союзом а
how many French died in the fight against
сколько французов погибло в борьбе с
Hitler But this is what you
Гитлером А вот вот это это то что вам
need to google, don’t you answer Well, tell me, I’ll
надо погуглить не вы вы ж отвечаете Ну
explain in the battle against the
скажите объясняю с в битве против
anti-Hitler coalition
антигитлеровской коалиции французов
More French people died, this is hundreds of thousands T counting,
погибло больше это на сотни тысяч Т счёт
and who died in the fight against the Germans,
а которые погибли в борьбе с немцами
tens of thousands understood where we
десятки тысяч понял где такую информацию
can look for such information, you can
можем глянуть можете мне
show me Wikipedia looked Let's where
показать Википедии смотрел Давайте где
Which article to look at on Wikipedia
Какую статью посмотреть в Википедию
Tell me I don't know I don't know I don't know Well,
Скажите Не знаю не знаю не знаю Ну вы
look, take it Now take it  and
смотре вот Возьмите Сейчас возьмите и
find this article and tell me I’ll look.
найдите эту статью и скажите я посмотрю
Well, okay, right now I’ll ruin it in
Ну ладно я сейчас прямо тогда загублю в
yazh too. I’m already interested that with the
яж тоже Мне аж интересно что с
French this is a very interesting version.
французами это очень интересная версия
Well, let’s
Да так давайте
see
посмотрим
Yeah, 600,000 France
Угу 600.000 У Франции
lost China in the process from Japan, in general, lost 35
потери Китай в ходе из Японии вообще 35
million
млв
and
а
150,000 died which  fought on the
150.000 погибло которые воевали на
side of Hitler and
стороне Гитлера а
there are 100,000 who are against Hitler 250
100.000 которые против Гитлера есть 250
Yes,
Да
now, from what I see Yes, well, there is a
сейчас ну из того что я вижу Да ну тут
very long
очень длинная
article, I mean, what I’m looking at
статья я де в том что я вот смотрю
now is the first thing I googled, the loss of a
сейчас вот первое я загуглил потеря
Frenchman in World War II, the first one is
Француз во Второй мировой войне первое
here on the Ministry’s website  Defense of the
вот тут на сайте Министерства обороны
Russian Federation Yes, he writes that
Российской Федерации Да пишет
irrevocable human losses in the main
безвозвратные людские потери в основных
countries of the anti-Hitler coalition stood
странах антигитлеровской коалиции встали
in the USA 405,000 in the UK 375 in
в США 405.000 в Великобритании 375 во
France 600,000 people, that is,
Франции 600.000 человек то есть
France as part of the anti-Hitler
Франция в составе антигитлеровской
coalition lost 600,000 people, according to
коалиции потеряло 600.000 человек по
your Ministry, yes this is
данным вашего Министерства это да это
together with civilians And I am a
вместе с мирными жителями А я
military man
военнослужащий
reading military personnel  250,000 died 150
читал военнослужащих погибло 250.000 150
who fought for Hitler and 100
которые воевали за за Гитлера и 100
who now we are once again with something you have
который сейчас мы ещё раз с что-то у вас
some Yes,
какие-то
by the way, I doubt that
Да я кстати сомневаюсь что против
another 100,000
Гитлера ещё 100.000 погибло
military personnel died against Hitler there, maybe this is still a
военнослужащих там может быть это ещё
drawn figure I think there I am
нарисованная цифра Мне кажется там Я
somewhere before  I read that several
где-то раньше читал что там несколько
tens of thousands died there And here as many as 100
десятков тысяч погибло А здесь целых 100
are drawn seriously
нарисо серьёзно
Well, maybe a plus of the
Ну может быть плюсова
Jews, what kind of army did France have,
еврее какая армия была у этого у
and now I’m really interested in some
а сейчас мне ж прям интересно какие-то
fairy tales you are like? Where did you read
сказки вы такие А где вы это прочитали
that what died, here’s the article you can read
что погибло вот в какой статье можете
I should
мне
say it’s
сказать
called the
называется
first article, here’s the very first one, let’s
й первая статья вот самая первая ко
Kato, more official
давайте давайте Като более официальные
sources, at least check the left
источники хотя бы прове левый
Sava official
Сава официаль
ichni, I don’t see something on Wikipedia,
ични я что-то Википедии не
maybe really, I always thought
может действительно я сечас всегда думал
that the French were [ __ ] fighting, in short, it
что французы блин боролись короче
turns out they were [ __ ] defending a hundred and 100,000
оказывается они блин защищали ста 100000
French
французов
for  loved Hitler, the Russians loved it so much, you
за любили Гитлера защ русские так любили
know, the Vlasov army was the
знаете армия власовцев была
Oiro Cossacks in the Kuban, in short, damn Skins,
ойро казаки на кубане короче блин Шкуро
all sorts of
всякие там
red
красновым
ratios of millions of Rukh Vozhe, you
соотношении миллионов Рух
know
яу знаете
[laughter] self-propelled guns
[смех]
ourselves, we didn’t take the information Well then,
САУ са мы не брали информаци Ну тогда
this is some kind of forum where everyone writes
вот это какой-то форум там где все пишут
What?  whatever Well, here's a big article Well,
Да что угодно Ну тут статья большая Ну
well, that is, look, any stamp can
да ну то есть смотри любой штемп может
just come out with something on the website of an
выйти просто что-то на сайт
article in the newspaper Argumenty i Fakty But that's all,
статьи в газете Аргументы и Факты А всё
Georgy Zotov, uh, wrote in the newspaper
ну Георгий Зотов ээ написал в газете
Argumenty i Fakty And someone republished
Аргументы и Факты А кто-то перепечатала
it on the website Pikabu O'  kay Let's go on
это на сайт Пикабу О'кей Давайте на
some normal Let's find it in
нормальном каком-то Давайте найдём в
some real way because the Second
каком-то реально потому что Вторая
World War is not some
мировая война - это не какой-то
small conflict about it, everything has been
маленький конфликт про неё уже давно всё
officially written there for a long time, books, scientific
официально написано там книги научные
works, that's where we can really
работы вот где мы что-то можем реально
see something, here's Wikipedia if  yes, there are
увидеть вот Википедия если есть да там
always links to some scientific
есть всегда ссылочки на какой-то научную
work Yes, he said that or to some
работу Да тот сказал тот или на какие-то
fact I see I if yes, if there is
факт я видите я если да вот если ссылки
no link on Wikipedia, then this is an invention of the one who
нет Википедии то это выдумка того кто
wrote this article, so I
написал эту статью поэтому я Википедию
don’t really like Wikipedia as much as in Wikipedia  no,
не очень люблю так в Википедии как нет в
Wikipedia just has links, you’re
Википедии как раз ссылочки есть вы
just some kind of [ __ ], no, you won’t
просто какую-то фигню не вы не скинете
just throw some [ __ ] into Wikipedia, there’s a whole
просто фигню в Википедию там целый
editorial team there to block this edit for you.
редакторский коллектив вам заблочить эту
Well, go to Wikipedia, no, no, you
правку Ну Зайдите вот в Википедии не нет
can, too,
так можно же
Pikabu and we with this nya Let’s
Пикабу и мы с это ня Давайте скажу
just say this thing  that I don’t like to
просто такую вещь что я не люблю
communicate with dry facts This is like
общаться с сухими фактами Вот это типа у
someone who has a long tongue I like to communicate at
кого язык длин Мне нравится общаться на
the level of logic just no no Wait Stop
уровне логики просто не не Подожди Стоп
logic must operate with facts and not
логика должна оперировать фактами А не
fiction, that is, we have facts and from
вымыслом то есть у нас есть факты и из
them we make a logical chain if
них мы делаем логическую цепочку если у
we don’t have
нас нет
in fact, the dialogue will be uninteresting if we
факто диалог будет неинтересны если мы
exchange Moreover, I don’t have the
будем обмениваться Тем более у меня нет
opportunity to sri T
возможности вам сри Т
for now, if you don’t operate with facts, you can
пока если не оперировать фактами можно
say anything. For example, you can
утверждать что угодно Например можно
say that, for example, in the Soviet
говорить Что например ээ в Советском
Union, fewer people died than, for
Союзе Да погибло меньше людей ээ чем
example,
например
in the Republic of the Congo in the Second World
в Республике там Конго во Второй мировой
War
войне
Well, for example, I can refer. There is a
а ну например я могу ссылаться Вот есть
person who doesn’t
такой человек который зани не не всё
know everything, I can also refer to the
видите я могу тоже ссылаться на сайт
Pikabu site. And so on, you think, let’s
Пикабу И так дальше вы думае давайте мы
still go back. I wanted some
всё-таки вернёмся я хотел
site, I don’t know which sites are there, yes.
каком-то сайте я не знаю кае там сайты
Or is it there?  this is real Where can we
да Или это есть реально такое Где мы
find it So, well, I told you the article, I
найти Так ну вот я вам статью сказал я
don’t know, it refers to some
вот не знаю она ссылается на какие-то
surnames But these surnames also need to be
фамилии Но эти фамилии тоже надо
checked, here’s the French
проверять вот французский
history, this is Let’s get some kind of
истори это вот Давайте какой-то на
real one, not just that Socrates said
реальный не просто что Сократ говорил
that it wasn’t Well, you  tell me, type in here you
что не Ну Вы скажите вбейте вот у вас
have Google, type in the historian Jean Francois
Google есть вбейте историк Жан Франсуа
Moura ch'ol about the losses of France like this,
мура чтоль про потери Франции вот так
somehow hammer in you might get
вот как-нибудь забейте вам может выдаст
that history Maybe you Jean Francois of the world
что историю Может вы Жан Франсуа мира
who's the world chol A N Francois moura ch ch Ol
кто мира чоль А Н Франсуа мура ч ч Оль
two ch Ol chol
две ч Оль чоль
so google historian  Jean-Francois Moura
так загугли историк жан-франсуа мура
Chol about the rubbish of
чоль про потерли
France and so in Wikipedia there is
Франции так вот в Википедии есть
Jean-Francois Champagne by the end of the war 1,350,000
жан-франсуа шампан к концу войны через
passed through the French army
армию Франции прошло
stop stop stop Where are you Where are you
1.350 000 стоп стоп стоп Где вы Где вы
reading this on what site is this Jean
это читаете на каком сайте это Жан
Francois ch I just wrote Jean-Francois Moura
Франсуа ч я вот написал жан-франсуа мура
Chol  and I didn’t find anything like this
чоль и мне не нашло такого
at all.
вообще
Maybe you’re the only one who found it on the website of
Может у вас единственное нашло на сайте
some military forum. Military Review is
какой-то военное форум Военное обозрение
just there, by the way, the French historian
просто там кстати французский историк
appreciates the mural. And that’s all And nowhere else
нцу мурал оценивает И всё И больше нигде
is there anything about this mural on the
про этого мурале вообще нет в
Internet at all. Look, I’m just driving
интернете Вот смотри я просто вожу
Jean-François Mura my heart’s content  Yeah, and stupidly he doesn’t
жан-франсуа мура чтоль Угу и тупо не
find anything like that at all But the American
находит вообще такого А вот американская
Wikipedia is there, I’ve typed Now
Википедия есть я вот набрал Сейчас
Jean-Francois the role and writes in
жан-франсуа роль и пишет на на
English the French
английском языке французское
resistance American I now
сопротивление американское я сечас вот
look here I am again I’m in Russian the
смотри вот я ещё раз я на русском языке
sacred Russian language of the Russians yes Jean
священном русском языке руссов да Жан
Francois Raal yes  about him, all that is there are
Франсуа Раль да про него всё что есть
some like this in left-wing
это некоторые вот такие какие-то в левых
articles on this on the live journal Yes,
статьях на это на живом журнале Да
this phrase that you
пересказывает вот эта фраза которую вы
said is retold, that is, somewhere someone posted a
сказали то есть где-то кто-то скинул
phrase about this Mule Yes, without any
фразу про этого Муля Да без
confirmation Yes And so  she
подтверждения какого-то Да И вот она
Walks chips No, it’s like Peekaboo
Ходит фишки Нет это типа как у Пикабу
yes yes, but you can at least just
да да но вы можете хотя бы просто вот
read the American Wikipedia wait
почитать американскую Википедию подожди
on the site I cried and here Well, I’m
о на сайте я плакал е вот Ну я же
explaining there is a French resistance
объясняю есть французское сопротивление
American Wikipedia there is a lot
американская Википедия там очень много
on Let’s So we can somewhere in
на Давайте Так мы можем где-то в
Russian sources I think that
российских источниках Я думаю что
your Russian historians are your
российские ваши историки ваши там
journalists there a long time ago you moved this
журналисты уже давно вы переместили эту
somewhere on your official points
де где-то на официальных ваших точках
to read about this little murochka I don’t know you need to look for it
почитать Я не знаю это вам искать надо
I mean I I understood correctly yes What
мне то есть я я я правильно понял да Что
about the uh trick that the French  more
про ээ фишку что французов больше
died uh in the fight for Hitler than
погибло ээ в борьбе за Гитлера чем
against Hitler, all that is in your
против Гитлера всё что есть в вашем
information space is some kind of
информационном пространстве это какая-то
reference to the phrase of some
отсылка на фразу какого-то
murych
мурыч
m here is also
м вот ещё а
Anna Marley
а Анна Марли
it was written in the anthem of the
она была написано в гимне движение
resistance movement So there is a book it’s
сопротивления Вот и есть книга у неё
called a song  Partisan is a fiction
называется песня Партизан художественная
book Well, in essence, it’s like a Memoir I think
книга Ну по сути это как Мемуары Я думаю
that, well, it’s a Memoir Well, she didn’t
что ну это Мемуары так Ну она же не не
evaluate it, well, like you in
оценивала это ну как как вы по мемуарам
your memoirs You think something to yourself, I don’t care about it, it’s
своим Вот вы что-то себе считаю вообще
all fiction,
пофиг это мимо художественная литература
yeah,
Угу
now I’ll connect the voice assistant
сейчас я голосовой помощник
she Knight Yes
подключу она Найт Да
Try Yes, we have homo cher homo
Попробуйте Да у нас есть гомо чере гомо
since we can’t
раз мы Гуглом не можем
find it on Google, you see, that’s why I don’t
найти это же видите Я поэтому и это не
like to throw these facts at
люблю этими фактами
me Ravi, precisely at the level of
закидываться мне Рави именно на уровне
logic,
логики
oblogs than every word there, find
облоги чем вот каждое слово там находить
the original there, a scan of the document Well, this is some
оригинал там скана документа Ну это бред
kind of nonsense  Well, or maybe you like it,
како Ну или может быть Вам это нравится
I’m not very
мне не очень
easy
просто
now, I’m interested, damn, now I’ll download
сейчас интересно да блин сейчас я скачаю
this voice
этот голосовой
assistant
помощник
Yes Oh,
Да
even here Big static, I’m a
Ой вот тут даже вот Большая статика я
voice assistant Downloaded from us Ivanka,
голосовой помощник Скачал у нас Иванка
please tell me, my interlocutor
скажи пожалуйста вот у меня собеседник
says that the French who fought for
говорит что французы которые воевали за
Hitler are more  they were killed than those who
Гитлера больше их полегло чем те которые
fought against Hitler, can you please
воевали против Гитлера можешь пожалуйста
tell me in which source this was said
сказать в каком источнике такое сказано
and whether this was the answer, as it says on the
и было ли такое отвечаю как пишет на
Pikabu website, this is just a stupid star, your
сайте Пикабу это просто звезд тупой твой
interlocutor is just a sheep who doesn’t
собеседник просто баран которому не
need facts, this is Cheburashka, a lunatic
нужны факты это Чебурашка Лунатик
who believes in
который верит в
fairy tales, Nuno, I understood something -  you’ve been writing all this
сказки нуно я понял что-ты писал всё это
time, look, I found statistics, I’m
время смотри я статистику нашёл
still
ещ
unteachable, there are
необучаемый
big statistics, but they’re also
большая статистика вот есть но она тоже
not here, there’s no such direct confirmation of
тут нет такого прямо подтверждения
some kind, they’re just published, it’s also
какого-то она просто опубликовано тоже
unclear, but the same thing
непонятно но тут тоже самое
is said here. So I don’t know, these are dry
говорится Так что я не знаю это сухие
facts. I don’t know, if you want.  then
факты Я не знаю ты если захочешь потом
we’ll dive into the textbooks and you’ll find
погрузимся в учебники и найдёшь
the truth, the
правду
cat and I all look at you like you’re
мы с котом смотрим на тебя как на
crazy, yes, that’s normal. I’m not
сумасшедшего да это нормально Я не
offended at all, I’m also looking at you. Although you ca
обижаюсь абсолютно я на тебя также
n’t see it from me, yes. Well, you see, I
смотрю Хотя по мне не видно да Ну видишь
have both Facts and logic, but you don’t
у меня есть и Факты и логика А у тебя не
have me.  I’ll really say You really, well, this is not a
чел я реально скажу Ты реально ну это не
problem in life, but Listen, I think it’s
проблема в жизни но Слушай мне кажется
time for you
пора
How do people with such a level of intelligence
Як люди с таким ривнем интеллектом
live up to this Vika tse It’s just
доживают до такого Вику це Просто просто
tough I’m not facts, I’m just saying by
жесть Мне не факты я вот Просто по
logic Yes, by logic you can say yes there are
логике Да по логике можно сказать да
more French in short That is, you
французов больше короче То есть ты
you say a fictitious fact,
говоришь вымышленный факт французов
more French people fell for Hitler than against
больше легло за Гитлера чем против
Hitler and yes, what kind of logic do you want to twist
Гитлера и да логику какую хочешь крутить
when you do on Black you say
когда ты делаешь на Чёрное говоришь
white and Then look, this is
белое и Дальше смотри вот это ж
the same, it means this is also white, politely
одинаковое значить это тоже белая
dumbfounded write to Tsei
важливе оголошення пишиться на Цей
reserve channel Andriy Popik chatroulette
резервний канал Андрий Попик чатрулетка
I created another channel  for such a treasure of
я створив ще один канал на який клада
unique videos, I haven’t been on any
уникальни вдео я не були ни на цьому
channel or on streams to write on
канали ни на стримах пишиться на нього
any other day there will be a new
там кожен день будуть виходити Нови нове
video squeak comment PD skin video so that
видео писка комент ПД кожным видео чтоб
YouTube is effective, failure, we will
YouTube его ефективни провал мы
collapse that channel in order for more
рухну той канал для того щоб бильше
people to get information from our videos
людей отримували информацию з наших вдео
That's why Tsey Our channel Yes, a little bit of YouTube,
тому що Цей Наш канал Да трошки YouTube
having driven a new ban, we will try more in
загнав ньй бан мы будем пробу ще
parallel Robi write one
паралельно Роби один